{
    "quizz": [
        {
            "question": "Which of the following companies get the government's passport project worth $1 Billion?",
            "options": ["Wipro", "Infosys", "TCS", "HCL"],
            "correct": "TCS"
        },
        {
            "question": "PM Modi has inaugurated a new campus of Chittaranjan National Cancer Institute (CNCI) in which city?",
            "options": ["Hyderabad", "Kolkata", "Patna", "Lucknow"],
            "correct": "Kolkata"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following type of class allows only one object of it to be created?",
            "options": [
                "Virtual class",
                "Abstract class",
                "Singleton class",
                "Friend class"
            ],
            "correct": "Singleton class"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a type of constructor?",
            "options": [
                "Copy constructorz",
                "Friend constructor",
                "Default constructor",
                "Parameterized constructor"
            ],
            "correct": "Friend constructor"
        },

        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
            "options": [
                "Base class pointer cannot point to derived class.",
                "Derived class pointer cannot point to base class",
                "Pointer to derived class cannot be created.",
                "Pointer to base class cannot be created."
            ],
            "correct": "Derived class pointer cannot point to base class"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statement is correct about the references?",
            "options": [
                "reference must always be initialized within functions.",
                "A reference must always be initialized outside all functions.",
                "A reference must always be initialized.",
                "Both A and C."
            ],
            "correct": "A reference must always be initialized."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statement is correct?",
            "options": [
                "A reference is stored on heap.",
                "A reference is stored on stack.",
                "A reference is stored in a queue.",
                "A reference is stored in a binary tree."
            ],
            "correct": "A reference is stored on stack."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statement is correct?",
            "options": [
                "A referenced has to be de-referenced to access a value.",
                "A referenced does not need to be de-referenced to access a value.",
                "A referenced has to be double de-referenced to access a value.",
                "Whether a reference should be de-referenced or not depends on the type of the reference."
            ],
            "correct": "A referenced does not need to be de-referenced to access a value."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is correct about class and structure?",
            "options": [
                "class can have member functions while structure cannot.",
                "class data members are public by default while that of structure are private.",
                "Pointer to structure or classes cannot be declared.",
                "class data members are private by default while that of structure are public by default."
            ],
            "correct": "class data members are private by default while that of structure are public by default."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following concepts means waiting until runtime to determine which function to call?",
            "options": [
                "Data hiding",
                "Dynamic casting",
                "Dynamic binding",
                "Dynamic loading"
            ],
            "correct": "Dynamic binding"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following concepts is used to implement late binding?",
            "options": [
                "Virtual function",
                "Operator function",
                "Const function",
                "Static function"
            ],
            "correct": "Virtual function"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following factors supports the statement that reusability is a desirable feature of a language?",
            "options": [
                "It decreases the testing time.",
                "It lowers the maintenance cost.",
                "It reduces the compilation time.",
                "Both A and B."
            ],
            "correct": "Both A and B."
        }
    ]
}
